### Contact

89929113 (Mobile) acsanchez2909@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/luis-alonsocedeño-sanchez-b5a64b71 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Management
Front-end Development
Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

### Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
Ingles (Native or Bilingual)
Portuguese (Professional Working)

### Certifications

Learn JavaScript Course
Learn Sass Course
Learn Intermediate JavaScript
Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)
Scrum Master Certified (SMC)

# Luis Alonso Cedeño Sanchez

Front-End Developer - Scrum Master - SEO - Senior Content Developer

Costa Rica

# Summary

I bring strong problem-solving, troubleshooting, and analytical skills that have shown to improve websites for various clients, and my creative approach to front-end web development has yielded positive feedback from both users and clients of websites I have worked on.

I gained experience, creating and rolling out new software programs and tools, and training and managing staff through software and system implementations while analyzing strategies and processes to facilitate improved operations and efficiency. I am a resourceful individual with excellent problem-solving skills.

During my 7+ years in the website development field, I have had the opportunity to strengthen my knowledge of front-end languages and frameworks, including JavaScripts, CSS, AJAX, jQuery, and Bootstrap.

With my educational background and my technical and customer service skills, I am in an excellent position to ensure all client's requirements. I'd love to use my leadership abilities to help teams to perform their best work.

# Experience

Prodigious Latin America Senior Content Editor March 2020 - Present (2 years 5 months) Costa Rica

My background in developing and editing online articles, blogs, and B2B/B2C websites for both startups and established companies prepares me to substantially impact your business. With my history of success creating a content strategy and monitoring traffic and analytics, along with my commitment to ensuring overall content alignment with brand and corporate guidelines. Experience defining product requirements, roadmaps, and long-

term strategies that satisfy company requirements as well as the client asks, and coordinated global teams to achieve product releases.

Highlights of my experience include the following:

- Expert in Agile methodology (Scrum & Kanban).
- Designing web pages and managing and editing comprehensive, fresh content for websites as the content manager for PDG, respectively; overseeing content development and leveraging analytics to maximize the effectiveness and quality of user experiences and increase site usage and usability.
- Working collaboratively with cross-functional business teams to manage site designs and maintain consistent messaging and branding across all sites.
- Establishing and continually updating editorial calendars, content and design guidelines, and rules for governance.
- Training, coaching, and managing CMS users and content providers; editing and proofreading all copy.
- Developed project scope and milestones using project management software like JIRA.
- Facilitated communication between the scrum team and product owner on a regular basis.

#### **JAZZGS**

Content Lead & SEO Optimization January 2020 - March 2020 (3 months)

Costa Rica

My background in developing and editing web content, articles, and features on a variety of subjects positions me to substantially impact your team. With my extensive technical proficiencies, my outstanding copyediting skills, and my experience in multimedia and digital content.

Highlights of my experience include the following:

- Developing compelling, targeted content for JAZZGS, adhering to style guidelines, and driving maximum audience traffic to content.
- Creating and updating original web content, digital signage, and social media copy while including video, photography, graphics, and other multimedia tools
- Leveraging WordPress and Adobe Creative Suite to digitally modify and enhance content.
- Reviewing Google Analytics to improve user experiences, revitalize web content, and maximize SEO.

- Working collaboratively with writers, contributors, freelancers, graphic designers, IT staff, and marketers.
- Employing exceptional editing skills to generate professional, error-free copy.

Profi Lead Web Developer April 2017 - November 2019 (2 years 8 months)

Costa Rica

My professional experience includes bringing the wireframes of the UX designer to life through HTML5 and CSS3, as well as collaborating with Back End Developers to create a stellar finished product. Coordinating and leading teams and processes to achieve—or surpass—defined organizational objectives. From assigning tasks and training team members to coordinating meetings and preparing reports, I excel at establishing goals, collaborating with cross-functional departments, and inspiring teams to exceed personal and corporate objectives.

Here are some of my most relevant qualifications and accomplishments:

- Identifying the strengths and weaknesses of all team members, leveraging each individual contributing member accordingly to maximize their impact and organizational gain.
- Delivering performance feedback and coaching leadership while coordinating and facilitating training and development needs to improve team member performances.
- Developed and Implemented project scope and timelines based on the design-develop-deploy process.
- Collaborated with UX designers and Back End Developers and ensured coherence between all parties.
- Working collaboratively with cross-functional business teams to manage site designs and maintain consistent messaging and branding across all sites.
- Establishing and continually updating editorial calendars, content and design guidelines, and rules for governance.
- Training, coaching, and managing CMS users and content providers; editing and proofreading all copy.
- Crafted various website features using HTML5 CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Tested feature prototypes for bugs and user experience.

HP

**Technical Support Analyst** 

January 2016 - January 2017 (1 year 1 month) Heredia

My professional experience includes installing and configuring many different computer systems, successfully identifying and solving previously undiscovered hardware and software problems, meticulously documenting each fix and update for future reference, using a variety of advanced diagnostic tools, keeping systems secure and up to date, and assisting both colleagues and customers with a variety of technical issues.

The following are some highlights of my experience and qualifications:

- Worked directly with customers as a technical support representative for Hewlett Packard.
- Worked as an in-house technical support associate for BIMBO company.
- Helped hundreds of customers solve problems with their home and work computers, software, and hardware.
- Fixed office computer systems as well as individual work computers.
- Kept accurate documentation of each case.
- Followed up with customers and colleagues to ensure that no further issues had arisen.
- Successfully resolved more than 350 troubleshooting tickets in a timely manner.
- Solved a variety of intricate technical, network, and printer issues.
- Gained expertise in diagnostics, end-user support, and problem identification.

BAC Credomatic Collections Specialist September 2013 - April 2014 (8 months) San José

My background includes solid experience sending customer invoices, processing payments, identifying past-due accounts, and resolving general billing issues and concerns while ensuring a superior level of customer service. With a strong foundation in customer account review and collection, my problem-solving and interpersonal talents.

Highlights of my background include:

• Ensuring billing operational efficiency and accuracy as a Billing Clerk for Bac San José, skillfully analyzing and handling invoices, payments, and financial records while responding to and quickly resolving customer billing inquiries.

- Placing collection calls when necessary to customers with open balances, focusing on past-due account payments.
- Receiving and processing incoming cash and check payments and ensuring meticulous and accurate documentation in customer payment records.
- Communicating directly and courteously with customers to review and verify billing data and facilitate timely payments.
- Leveraging my superior analytical, interpersonal, and organization skills to achieve outstanding results.
- With my strong experience in accounts receivable and collections, coupled with keen financial acumen and dedication to customer service excellence, I am confident that I could quickly exceed your expectations.

## Education

**Universidad Cenfotec** 

Course, Web Development Javascript · (2018 - 2018)

INA

Design and web development, Technician · (2012 - 2015)

Liceo de Curridabat

Bachelor's degree · (2002 - 2009)

Intensa - Language Institute

English Language and Literature, General